Building Production Enterprise-Grade Frontend/backend Applications



Summary

With more than 4 years of experience with the IT Industry, I do bring sound technical knowledge, a curious mind and generosity with me. I have worked on a **broad set of technology** including frontend, backend, Cloud platform engineering and DevOps.

I strongly believe in creating a healthy, fun and result-oriented culture wherever I go without any bias/discrimination. Building state-of-the-art *Enterprise-Grade Production ready* software applications has always been the main motto. Also, I love contributing & sharing my knowledge to developer communities through blogging, micro-blogging on twitter/linkedin and other online/offline platforms. I am also a part of the *AWS Community Builder Program*. Hold Certifications on *HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate* and *AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate*.

Skills

Deep understanding in Information Technology (Infrastructure, Architecture, Development,
Performance, Scalability, 12 factor methodology)
Programming: OO JavaScript / JavaScript (ES4, ES5, ES6, ES7), Node.js, Webpack tooling,
Babel Transpiler,
SASS, ESLint, Apache/Nginx, HTML5/CSS3, jQuery, MYSQL, AWS RDS, Bash, Shell,
Groovy, C, C++, OO PHP/Laravel, Core JAVA, Java Springboot, Python, Linux Command,
Mongo Atlas
Framework: MEVN, MEAN, Vue.js, Java Springboot Basic, Laravel
Cloud Technologies: AWS Cloud Cloudformation, AWS Lambda, AWS API Gateway, AWS
EC2,
Docker, Cloudflare worker, Serverless Integration
IDE / Text Editor used: Github Codespace, VS Code, Nano, Vim
Practical mindset. Self-taught in web environment or new technologies (DevOps,
Performance, Programming language)
Managing project (GitLab, Jira, Bitbucket, Github, AGILE Scrum / Kanban agility)
Expert knowledge to solve problems (debugging)
Leadership spirit in development / IT
Continuous Integration / Continuous Development (Jenkins, Udeploy)

Education

Centre for Development of Advanced Computing

Feb 2019 - Aug 2019

Postgraduate-Diploma in Advanced Computing

Top 5 Ranker INDIA wide.

Subjects: Data Structure, C++, JAVA, Springboot, JavaScript, Angular, C# .Net Core, Database, AWS Cloud

Gujarat Technological University

Mar 2013 - Feb 2017

Bachelor of Engineering of Information Technology CGPA 8.2

Microsoft Student Partner Campus Ambassador

Work Experience

Blazeclan Technologies (Pune, INDIA)

Aug 2021 - Present

Sr. Cloud Application Developer

- Worked for Malaysia based Product firm ASTRO MEASAT Broadcast Network Systems to integrate Netflix Partner OTT services.
- Backend development on AWS cloud services like APIGateway, Lambda, DynamoDB, SNS, SQS,etc and nodejs microservice function.
- ☐ Maintaining code with quality and performance optimization
- ☐ Unit testing with Mocha, Chai, Jest
- Setting up Bitbucket CICD Pipeline & Logging services like AWS Opensearch Kibana.
- ☐ Working with Scalable SQS queuing services with different microservices related to Netflix OTT

Morningstar, Inc. (Navi Mumbai, INDIA)

Aug 2019 - July 2021

Software Engineer

- Worked on company owned software products named Morningstar Goalbridge and MoneyTalk chatbot.
- Full stack developer in Javascript (Node.js, Vue.js, Express.js, React.js basic, Vanilla JS)
- ☐ Using Webpack, ES5 & ES6, NPM, YARN, SCSS
- ☐ Unit test with Mocha, Chai, Jest
- ☐ Building Accessible websites as per the Web Content Accessibility Guidelines 2.0.
- Docker / NPM / ES6 / Regex / Docker / Splunk / Jira / Jenkins / GitHub / Postman / VS Code / PostgreSQL / Confluence Tools / Nexus
 Repository / SONAR Code Coverage Analysis / Checkmarx Vulnerability Scan / New Relic Monitoring / Heap.io traffic Monitoring / VictorOps
 / IBM Urban Code Udeploy Multi-Environment based projects Dev, Staging, UAT, Production
- Morningstar Web Component, Lerna MonoRepo, Storybook Web component, Design System.
- ☐ Git / CI / CD / Unit tests and integration tests, automation test with Nightwatch.js
- API REST and Universal Auth0 Authentication/Authorization Setup for all different applications.
- Agility Kanban and Scrum
- AWS Kinesis Kafka for Splunk integration to ingest Cloudwatch Logs.
- AWS S3 Site Deployment with Serverless Integration with AWS LAMBDA functions, DynamoDB, AWS Cloudwatch Logs & Alerts, Cloudformation Stack, etc.
- API debouncing, Site Resource Optimization
- Worked on Moneytalk Chatbot web app prototype/POC along as per the Wireframe designs.
- Worked on Massive Morningstar Goalbridge Web Application with Cloud Serverless Infrastructure Backend, Micro-Frontends with Storybook UI Tooling.
- Code refactoring, Pull Request Code Review, Passing Sonarqube code quality checks, fixing node packages vulnerabilities detected by Checkmarx tool.
- Mentoring Juniors at Technical Coaching Institute and Blogging, writing technical articles.

DQUIP CRM (Mumbai, INDIA)

Sep 2017 - Nov 2018

Software Engineer

- Worked on company owned CRM Softwares for Insurance, Automobile, Real Estate and Support System.
- PHP, HTML, Jquery, Laravel, Wordpress, LAMP Stack
- Designing MySQL Databases and CRM Web Application
- Working closely with CTO in web application planning & database design.
- Implementing various REST API Integration into CRM App.
- Building custom libraries and plugin for integration with 3rd party.
- ☐ Fullstack Role with backend and frontend development
- ☐ Using AWS EC2, RDS, SES for CRM WebApp.
- Server configuration (Nginx), linux configuration and setup

Vista Sofft E Designs Pvt Ltd (Mumbai, INDIA)

Apr 2017 - Aug 2017

Junior Web Developer

- Languages used: Vanilla JS, PHP Object, SQL, HTML
- ☐ Vanilla JS, HTML, CSS, and Photoshop, Jquery, AJAX
- Training in Wordpress framework and worked on Site Maintenance, feature addition and bug fixing
- ☐ Worked on Ecommerce Website UI Design
- ☐ Used phpMyAdmin (SQL DB), FileZilla Client
- ☐ Digitalisation of the company via SEO (Google, social medias, new trends)
- ☐ Working closely with the CTO to understand Project requirements.